Have you heard
Drink more water when you can
drinking more water won't do any harm
Wait a mininute
Drinking too much water can cause problems
Did you know
A junior high school student
He went to attend
his parents' company's spring party
There will be a water drinking competition on that day
To win
the 6000 prize
Did you know
He drank 60 glasses of water in 30 minutes.
Probably
6000cc of water
After returning home
Dizziness, vomiting, convulsions
The whole person is very uncomfortable
Send him to the hospital immediately
Wow, this is too scary.
Hu Naiwen starts his lecture
I am your old friend, Doctor Hu
I want to share this episode with you
1.Drinking more water is fine, but drinking the wrong amount can damage your kidneys and heart
2.Swollen face and cold feet, it turns out that the water is stuck
3.Drink life-saving water like this to prevent cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases
4.Are you secretly lacking water? Get the clue from 1 place
5.In these 3 situations, remember to drink more water
Drink more water, it's okay
Drinking the wrong amount may damage your kidneys and heart
The last time we took the MRT
See a young man
He filled a kettle
Very large
Looks like 1500cc
People are very particular now
Have drunk enough water today?
How many cc drink per day?
I don't encourage you
to drink too much water.
The junior high school student I just mentioned
Just drank more water
almost lost life.
fine
Finally the hospital saved him.
It saved his kidneys.
Fortunately, everyone is OK.
Don't drink too much
We should drink normally.
Nothing will happen
The kidneys are like the body's floodgates
Responsible for filtering blood every day
Drain excess water
and metabolic waste products
Up to 18 liters of urine can be excreted per day
This process is not just about detoxification
Maintains body water
Balance with electrolytes
However,
he kidneys have a limited drainage rate.
If within a short period of time
For example, within 3 hours
Drink more than 2 liters of water
The kidneys may not be able to process it in time
Causes water retention
and electrolyte imbalance
Further leading to acute water intoxication
In this case
It could be life-threatening.
Summer is so hot
Many people carry large kettles
Drink a lot of water
But if the kidneys
can't keep up with the metabolism
The water will be retained in the body
You might say
Isn't the purpose of drinking water to replenish water
in the body and preserve it?
Everyone
Things are not as simple
as fools think.
attention
Drinking too much water may lead to
Swollen hands and feet, frequent urination, insomnia at night
Make the body more tired
Feeling tired the next day
Affects work efficiency
Swollen face, cold hands and feet
It's not about
drinking too little water
The point is not to drink more water
but rather whether it will be metabolized
How Chinese medicine views drinking water
It's not about how much drink
But the water drink
If too much
Can it be metabolized?
Cannot be metabolized
There is a problem
People with weak constitution
Poor spleen and stomach function
Drinking too much water
Cannot be absorbed or metabolized
Stuck in the body
Do you know what it will become?
Shī qì (Transliteration)
This type of person often has a characteristic
Drink water throughout the day
Mouth is still dry
Swollen face
Cold hands and feet
The water circulates in the body
but can't be excreted
In fact,
the human body has a built-in drinking alarm
called baroreceptors
Automatically detects
blood concentration
The blood thickens
When the osmotic pressure increases
The brain naturally
sends signals
I'm thirsty, I need water
Drink water at this time
It's what the body needs
When to rehydrate
How much water should we drink a day
How much water should you drink in a day?
There is actually no standard answer
It depends on your physical condition.
There is also a lifestyle to adjust
Listen to your body
More important than listening to numbers
If you sweat easily
Dry mouth
People with hot body constitution
The water demand is naturally high
xū hán (Transliteration) constitution
Cold hands and feet
Prone to diarrhea
Not suitable for drinking a lot of water
You should drink warm water slowly
Avoid damage to the spleen and kidneys
From the daily perspective
Do you stay in an air-conditioned room all day?
How much exercise do you do?
Is there a lot of sweating?
These can affect your needs
How much water to drink
Drink life-saving water like this
Prevent cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases
Drink a glass of life-saving water when you wake up in the morning
Why
You didn't drink water all night.
After a full night's sleep
The body is in a state of slight dehydration
After getting up in the morning
This is when the blood is thickest
and blood pressure is highest.
easily gets clogged
I know
Drink warm
Warm your stomach and heart
Good. Well said.
Come
Just drink this cup
200cc warm water
Please drink slowly.
Allow water to be absorbed
by the body gradually
Don't drink it all in one go.
Otherwise the blood will be diluted by you
It puts more burden
on the heart and kidneys.
Why is this glass of water
so important?
Because it has three key functions
No. 1
Replenish the water you lose overnight
Restoring balance in the body
Second
Awakening dormant internal organs
Warm up your body slowly
Third
Helps the intestines clear waste
Promote bowel movements
Before you go out to work
The body should work first
Get rid of toxins
People will become lighter
More spirited
In the morning,
you can drink lemon water and honey water
Change your taste occasionally
Of course, no problem.
But sugary drinks
or oily drinks
Can't drink every day
Because these ingredients
May make the blood thicker
Increase the burden on the body
It can't replace boiled water.
Are you quietly lacking water?
Seeing clues from 1 place
Want to know if you are drinking enough water?
The simplest way to judge
Just check the color of your urine
What if the color is darker?
The darker the urine
The greater the possibility of water shortage
There are four levels
You can tell the difference this way
1.Urine is clear and colorless
It means you drank too much water.
Urine is diluted
Stay hydrated
You can drink less water at this time.
2. Urine is light yellow
If you are like this
Then congratulations to you.
It means you are in great condition.
Adequate water intake and normal metabolism
Keep it up
3. Urine is dark yellow to orange
Represents body water
A little bit not enough
You need water.
Avoid further dehydration
4.Urine is dark orange
Or even brown.
Severe water shortage
Possible effects on the kidneys or liver
At this time
Drinking water is not enough
If it is dark brown
It may be that the liver metabolism is abnormal.
See a doctor as soon as possible
If your urine is unusual in color
No improvement after drinking water
Or have other discomfort
Please see a doctor immediately
Ensure your health
Then you will ask me
Doctor Hu
When I get up in the morning
First urine color
It's also very yellow
Why is my urine yellow in the morning?
That's normal.
You didn't drink water all night.
Urine becomes more concentrated
So the first urine after waking up is yellowish
Don't worry
As long as you drink water next time
Urine color
It will gradually fade
If your urine is yellow all day long
You should pay attention to whether there is water shortage.
Sometimes eat
Dragon fruit
Will the color change?
yes
Dragon fruit color
It is water soluble
If there is too much, it will be excreted.
Maybe it will turn red
Maybe it will turn yellow
Maybe it will turn something
And what else
You took B complex
Or beetroot
This type of food or nutritional supplement
It may also let the color of urine
Turn yellow or red
so what
Don't see urine
get scared when it turns yellow or red
First, we need to rule out the influence of diet
Determine whether are really dehydrated.
These three situations
2-3 p.m.
Office workers sitting
From 2 to 3 p.m.
Are you starting to yawn?
just want to sleep.
At this time
Go to the tea room and get a glass of water
Help you refresh your mind
Focus
Make your afternoon work more efficient
2 When the body sweats
When you go to the sauna
Bathing and exercise will make you sweat
At this time, a lot of water is lost.
Remember to drink water to cool down
Regulating body temperature
3 When taking a plane
The air humidity on the plane is very low
Only about 20%
This will make your skin
Easily becomes dry and dehydrated.
Remember to drink water frequently during this time.
Friends who like this video
Please click "Super Thanks" below the video
Donate to support us
Your support
We all received it.